Guide to the Papers of Mark Popovskii,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Arranged Correspondence
  - Subseries III.5: Miscellaneous
    - Cate, Curtis; Cerni, Aleksandr; Chakovskii, A. B.; Chartschlaa, Platon; Chepliunova, Valentina; Chertok, Semen; Chichkan, Nadezhda; Choslovsky, Syd; Chow, David and Mary; Christoffers, Henry J.; Chudnovsky, Volf G.; Chudnovsky, David and Gregory; Chukovskaya, Lidia (outgoing); [Chyradia], John; Cogan, Aleksandr (Alex); Croucher, Murlin; Correspondence: C (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Danielian, Elena; Danzig, [...]; Davies, Richard; Davydova, Liudmila; Dechtiarenko, Luba; Dediukin, Sergei; Deikun, Aleksei; De Lima, Lisa; Demokhin, IU; Diczbalis, Sigizmund; Druskin, Lev; Dumas, Galina; Dunaiev, T.; Correspondence: D (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Edgerton, William; Edizioni Gruppo Abele; Elbert, Leonid; Elkonin-Johansson, Irina; Emel'ianov, Vasilii; Eniutina, Vera; [Eppen], Gella; Eremina, L. C.; Etingoff, Ievgenii; Eydinov, Yakov; Ezerskaia, Bella; Correspondence: E (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Fain, [...]; Fainberg, Nora; Fainberg, Vladimir; Fal'kovich, Volf; Fedorov, IUrii; Feldman, Zeylik; Filipp, Valeria; Filippov, Boris (and Zhiglevich, Ievgenia); Filips, K.; Flan, Liudmila; Foster, Liudmila; Frants, Elena; Freeman, Margaret; Fridman, Lawrence G.; Friedberg, Maurice; Correspondence: F (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Galanter, Boris; Galperin, Grigorii; Gantman, IUlian; Garbut, Kim; [Gee, Aurora]; Gendler, IUrii; Genieva, E. (re: Men'); Gert, IUrii; Gertsikov, Greg and Dora; Gessen, Elena; Gifford, Prosser; Ginsburg, V.; Girshin, Mark; Glad, John; Correspondence: Ga - Gn (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Goichman, Vladimir; Goldshtein, Leia; Golianskii, Grigorii; Golitsina, Nina; Golitsyn, Andrei; Gollerbakh, Sergei; Golubev, Daniil; Goodman, IUlii; Gordin, IAkov; Goriacheva, Viktoria; Gorshevsky, Boris; Gorokhovskaia, Elena; Gosteva, Alevtina; Grechishnik, Leonid; Grem, Irina; Grib, Sergei; Grigorenko, Zinaida; Grigorovich, Vadim; Grin, E.; Grosman, Ievgenii; Gurevich, Georgii; Gurevich, Leonid; Gurina, Tamara; Gusev-Mikhalev, Petr; Guyot, Daniel; Correspondence: Go - Gz (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Chauncy, D.; Hough-Ross, Richard; Iakovlev, Egor; Iankelevich, Tat'iana and Efrem; Il'in, A, IU (Mayor of Tambov); Ioffe, Solomon; Isaacs, Susan; Istomina, Aleksandra; Iur'ev, Zoia; Ivanov, S.; Jensen, Kenneth M.; Correspondence: H - J (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kafanova, L.; Kalina, Aleksandr; Kampova, [Marika]; Kapeliushnikov, [...] (Slava); Kaplan, Igor'; Karpova, Tat'iana; Kartasheva, Marina; Kashlinskaia, Galina; Kasinec, Edward; Katsenelinboigen, Aron J.; Kaup, Peeter V.; Kazak, V.; Kazhdan, Aleksandr; Khadzhinova, Nadezhda; Khait, Leonid; Khaselev, Vitalii Kheifets, Mikhail; Khoury, Lora; Kirsh, Boto; Kiseleva, Lida; Kitaevich, IUlii; Klimchak, Edward; Kogan, Mark; Kogan, Eric; Kolesnikov, Nikolai and Raisa; Komarov, Vladimir; Konashev, M. B.; Konson, Lev; Kopylova, Maia; Korobkova, Ievgeniia; Koshkarev, Zotik; Kozyreva, Natal'ia; Correspondence: Ka - Ko (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Krasnostchekova, Elena; Krasnov, Evgenii; Kreid, Vadim; Kresin, Vladimir; Krutovskaia, Lina; Krylova, Irina; Kryzhitskii, Sergei; Ktorova, Alla; Kudrova, Irma; Kunin, Isaak; Kupchenko, V; Kurz, Voldemar; Kvitash, Vadim; Correspondence: Kp - Kz (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Latynina, Alla; Lavrov, L.; Lavrova-Karelina, Lidia; Lemkhin, Mikhail; Leventon, Anatolii; Levin, Roman; Levitan, Efim; Levy, V.; Liberman, Anatolii; Linnik, IU (Tsentr po Isucheniyu Duhovnoi Kul'tury Gulaga); Lipkovich, IAkov; Liutova, Maia; Livshits, Marina; Lovell, John P.; Lukinchuk, Valerii; Lukishker, Edward; Lupalovskii, Oleg; Luryi, IUrii; Lackenbach Siegel Marzullo & Aronson, P.C. Correspondence: L (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Magnus, Margarita; Maksimov, Andrei; Maksimova, Tat'iana; Manin, Evgenii; Marcus, Stephanie (Library of Congress); Margolina, Anna; Markov family; Marshall, Eliot; Martsin, Anatolii; Maruts, Oleg; Maslennikova, Zoia; May, Lynn E.; Meerovich, Il'ia; Meiendorf, Ioann; Meier, IUrii (Meyer, George); Meier, Reinhard; Meisarosh, Georgina; Men', Pavel; Men', Natalia; Menaker, Tat'iana; Meniker, Elena; Meskin, Bella; Michelet, Michel; Mikhailov, Mikhaila; Mikhniuk, Galina; Miller, Larisa; Mininberg, David T.; Minuhin, Ella; Mirkovich, Elena; Mogendovich, [...]; Molodoi, Vadim; Momal, Claude; Moravets, S.; Moravskii, Nikita; Morozov, Vladimir; Muller-Dietz, Heinz E.; Muranova, Lidiia; Murav'eva, Irina; Correspondence: M (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Natkho, Kadyr; Neboga, Nadezhda; Neifakh, Aleksandr; Nikitin, M.; Nisenson, Boris; Nizhnikov, Margarita; Novoseletskaia, Fira; Nul'man, M.; Correspondence: N (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Obolenskii, Sergei; Obolonskii, Aleksandr; Ocheretianskii, Aleksandr; Oksman, Tat'iana; Olsuf'eva, Evgeniia; Orlova, Raisa; Ozerkov, P.; Ozernoy, Vladimir M.; Correspondence: O (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Pakh, Natal'ia; Pakh, Imre; Palant, Boris; Palm, Charles (Hoover Institution); Pashenkova, Marina; Petlakh, L.; Pirozhkova, Vera; Pleshko, Petr; Pliushch (Pliouchtch), Leonid; Poklitar, E. A.; Polchaninoff, R; Polenov, Vladimir; Poliak, Grigorii; Pomar, Mark; Popkin, Jim; Popova, Aleksandra; Potik, [...]; Pototskaia, Lidiia; Prikhod'ko, Natal'ia; Pruden, Natal'ia; Pundeff, Martin; Putz, Paul; Puzin, Nikolai (custodian of Tolstoy's museum at Iasnaia Poliana); Correspondence: P (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Rabichev, Lev; Rabkin, Iakov; Radunskaia, Irina; Radunskii, Victor; Radysh, Oksana; Rappoport, Gedda; Rappoport, Vitalii; Reddaway, Peter; Reitman, Mark; Ringland, Peter; Rodina, Elena and IUrii; Roiz, Maks; Rokhlin, Leonid; Romanov, Anatolii; Roitman, Anna; Rozin, M. A.; Rubinshtein, Igor'; Ruble, Blair A.; Rudiak, Ilia; Rudkevich, L. A.; Rumiantsev, A.; Rusakovskii, Samuil; Correspondence: R (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Saito, [...]; Salganick, Dolores; Sandler, Valerii; Sapozhnikov, Elena; Schaad, Rudolf; [Schneyd, Schlob]; Sechkarev, Vsevolod; Selezneva, Evgeniia; Shapoval family; Sharova, Anna; Sharp, Ben; Shchedrinskii, A.; Shirinkina, Ariadna; Shmeman, Aleksandr; Sholomova, S. B.; Shropshire (Rusakova), Liudmila; Shtein, Edward; Shterenberg, Bella; Shtern, IUrii; Shtivel, Ruslan; Shur, [...]; Shustov, Valentin; Sikorskii, Igor; Sil'ver, Raisa; Sil'vestrova, Svetlana; Simontova, Marianna; Sinkevich, Valentina; Skoblinskii, Aleksandr; Slavov, Atanas; Slonim, Anna; Smith, Lidia; Smith, Melissa; Smolianskii, IAkov; Correspondence: Sa - Sn (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Sokirko, Victor; Sokolov, Liubov' and Valerii; Solov'ev, Vladimir; Sominskii, Monus; Sonenshine, Tara; Soulson, Iosif; Stavitskii, Petr; Steinberg, Mark; Stoliarov, Isaak; Stoliarova, Marina; Strelkova, [...]; Suhih, Aleksei; Svechin, Grigorii; Sverdlin, Anatoliii; Svetlov, Felix; Svetlosanova, Isabella; Svetohovskii, Tadeush; Sviridov, Mikhail; Swildens, Helene; Sztein, Edward; Correspondence: So - Sz (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Takhtadzhian, Armen; Targan, Samuil; Temkina, Marina; Tison, Vera; Titer, Mark; Tokarev, Sergey; Tlomatsu, Solomon; Tolstaia, Ol'ga; Tolstoi, Ivan; Tontoya, Karen; Treml', Vladimir; Trofimov, Aleksandr; Trubetskoi, A; Tsauder, pavel; Tschernaiavskaia, Anna; Tsurupa, Aleksei; Tsurukova, Ol'ga; Tucker, Martin; Tverdynina, Ol'ga; Correspondence: T (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ulam, Adam; Ulanovskaia, Maia; Correspondence: U (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Vainer, Mikhail; Vainshtein, Ruvim; Vaksberg, Arkadii; Vaksman, Abram; van Doorn, Jack; Varlamov, Edward; Vasiliadou, Erica; Verbitskaia, Lina; Verner, Artur; Verkhovskii, Aleksandr; Vinogradov, Igor'; Vinokur, Bertol'd; Vinokurov, Zinovii; Vishnevetskii, I, (re: Men'); Voevodskaia, Kseniia; Vollfson, Stanislav; Volin (Ponomarev), Mikhail; Volkov, Solomon; Voll, John; Volodin, Boris; Von Wiren-Garczynski, Vera; Vorontsov, IUlii; Correspondence: V (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Waksman, Selman A.; Werbizky, George G.; White, Sara; Whitney, Thomas; Correspondence: W (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Young, Cathy; Zaitseva, Svetlana; Zaks, B.; Zalevskii, Georgii; Zaltsberg, Mak; Zarechniak, Dmitrii; Zarifian, Alla; Zerbino, Dmitrii; Zernov, Nikolai; Zhabkovskii, Evgenii; Zholkovskii, A.; Zorin, Aleksandr; Zusman, Vladimir; Correspondence: X - Z (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified - outgoing (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified - incoming (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Writings
  Typescripts and photocopies of typescripts for books, articles and lectures by Popovskii, book galleys, article clippings. Often with manuscript edits and notes by the author.
  - Subseries IV.1: Science and Ethics in USSR
    Arranged Chronologically
    - Vnachale Bylo Delo... Moscow, USSR, 1976, (Galleys, ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Vsgliad S Berega, Moscow, USSR, [1976], (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Chest' Uchenogo, Moscow, USSR, [1976], (Mock-up copy, ) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Speeches and Lectures, USSR, 1960s - 1970s (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Speeches and Lectures, 1978 - 1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Speeches and Lectures on Science in Gorbachev's and Post-Soviet Russia, 1987 - 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Chetvertyi Element (unfinished), New York, NY, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Vo Chto Verit Sovetskii Uchenyi, New York, NY, Sep. 1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Nauka I Vera - Opasnoeedinenie, New York, NY, Jan .1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Verit Li V Boga Sovetskii Uchenyi, New York, NY, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Uchenyi, Religiia I Perestroika, New York, NY, Jun. 1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Nauka V Epokhu Gorbacheva, New York, NY, Apr. 1989 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Begut (scientists leaving USSR), New York, NY, Feb. 1990 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Ukhtomskii, Aleksei Taina Akademika Alekseia Ukhtomskogo, New York, NY, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Uchenye - Tozhe Liudi, New York, NY, Mar. 1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Olsuf'ev, Nikolai Predatel'stvo, New York, NY, Jul. 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Sakharov, Andrei Moi Sakharov, New York, NY, May-96 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.2: Voino-Iasenetskii
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Life and Works of Voino-Iasenetskii - Book Proposal and Chapter 7, New York, NY, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Krest I Skal'pel, New York, NY, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Moi Liubimyi Geroi, New York, NY, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Voino-Iasenetskii, Valentin Fedorovich Miscellaeous on Voino-Iasenetskii, New York, NY, 1980 - 1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV.3: Haffkine
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Articles about Haffkine, New York, NY, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Tri Zhizni Doctora Khavkina, New York, NY, 1989, (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Tri Zhizni Doctora Khavkina, New York, NY, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      [Copy of 10 - 9]
  - Subseries IV.4: Tolstoy and Tolstovtsy
    Arranged chronologically
    - Tolstoy, Leo Kuda Devalis' Tolstovtsy, Moscow, USSR, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 1 - 2)
      [OVERSIZED]
    - Tolstoy, Leo Russkie Muzhiki Rasskazyvaiut, Moscow, USSR; Washington, DC; New York, NY, 1977 - 1981, (Edited typescript - photocopy, ) (Box 10, Folder 11)
      [Part of original 1987 gift by Popovskii.]
    - Tolstoy, Leo Eto Tvoi Deti, Lev Tolstoy, New York, NY, 1980 - 1981, (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Tolstoy, Leo Lectures on Tolstovtsy, 1980 - 1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IV.5: Religion
    - Men', Aleksandr Za Chto Traviat Otsa Aleksandra Menia, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Nash Khram, [1985] (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Bog, My I Svoboda Voli, Dec. 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Chuvstvo Tserkvi, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Men', Aleksandr Vot Kogo Ubili, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Krasnaia Dver', Jul. 1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Kniga I Luidi (on Bible), Oct. 1991 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Vera, Tserkov' I Moia Professiia, [1994] (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Meerson-Aksenov, Mikhail Prochnaia Pozitsiia Mezhdu Nebom I Zemlei (with notes), [1994] (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Mne Tyt Teplo, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Subseries IV.6: Sex in USSR
    - On, Ona I Sovetskii Rezhim, Version 1, New York, NY, [1980 - 1983], (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 11, Folder 1 - 2)
    - On, Ona I Sovetskii Rezhim, Version 2 (Chapter 12 missing), New York, NY, [1980 - 1983], (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 11, Folder 3 - 4)
    - On, Ona I Sovetskii Rezhim - notes., New York, NY, [1980 - 1983] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - On, Ona I Sovetskaya Vlast', New York, NY, n.d., (Edited Typescript - photocopy, ) (Box 21, Folder 4- 5)
      [This version was part of original 1987 gift by Popovskii. Filed with research materials.]
    - Love and Sex Soviet Style - Book proposal and translation of selected chapters, New York, NY, [1983] (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Love and Sex Soviet Style - typescript of Chapters 6, 8, 14, New York, NY, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Love and Sex Soviet Style - typescript of Chapters 6 - 14, New York, NY, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Lectures on Sex in USSR, 1982 - 1990 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV.7: Russians in America
    - Na Drugoi Storone Planety (collection of stories), New York, NY, n.d., (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Zvorykin, Vladimir Vstrecha s Ottsom Televidenia, Nov. 1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Industria Obol'sheniia, [1985] (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Na Drugoi Storone Planety, New York, NY, 1986, (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Zvorykin, Vladimir V Gostiakh U Izobretatelia Televiden'ia, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Lectures on Russians in America, 1987 - 1996 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Katsenelinboigen, Aron J. Dve Zhizni Arona Katsenelinboigena, Sep. 1988 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Kalina, Aleksandr Nash Chelovek V Kalifornii, Oct. 1988 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Sloenyi Pirog Na Kruglom Stole, Jan. 1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Nashi V Chicago, Nov. 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - V Poiskah Doinykh Korov (on perestroika and emigration), [1990] (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - My Amerikantsy - No Kakie (on 3rd Wave of Russian Emigration), Jul. 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - America - Nash Dom (4 articles on 5th wave of emigration), Jan. - Apr. 1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - A Mne Interesny Liudi, Sep. 1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Neokonchennaia Povest', Apr. 1996 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - My Zdes' Ne Pervye (on 1st and 2nd waves of Russian Emigration), Apr. 1998 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Prosveshchat' Ameriku? A Pochemu By I Net. (inventors), Apr. 1998 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Cherniakovskii, Mitchell Kogda ia Stanu Americanskim Generalom, Jun. 1998 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Semeinyi Portert, New York, NY, 2000, (Edited Typescript, ) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Subseries IV.8: Writers in Exile
    - Lectures on Writers in Exile, 1983 - 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Literaturniye Koshki-Myshki, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Znakom'tes' - Russkie Pisateli, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Ne Zabyvat' Ushedshikh (graves of emigration), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Lipkin, Semen Semenu Lipkinu - 75, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Dovlatov, Sergei Litsa I Maski, Mar. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Iazykom Tsitat, Feb. 1989 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Is Ameriki Vidnee, Dec. 1989 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Efimov, Igor' Uzhe Desiat' Let Plyvet Etot Korablik (on Hermitage publishing co.), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Genis, Aleksandr; Vail', Petr Pisateli I America, [1992] (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Rossiiskoe Pero V Amerikanskoi Chernil'nitse, Mar. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Dovlatov, Sergei K Voprosu o Nravstvennosti, Nov. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Sem' Knig Minuvshego Goda, [1994] (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Chetyre Knigi Odnogo Goda, Feb. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Nashi V Klivlende, Jul. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Pisateli V Mire Nechitaiushikh, Oct. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Brodsky, Joseph To, Chto Sokhranila Pamiat', Dec. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Pochemu Ia Ne Liubliu Slova Pisatel', Jun. 1997 - Dec. 1998 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Gorech' I Sladost' Moei Professii, Jul. 1998 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Bereg, Vernis', Mar. 1999 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      [On oral-literary magazine Bereg, created in 1979 by Russian writers in New York.]
  - Subseries IV.9: Miscellaneous Writings
    - Clippings, 1978 - 1999 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Book Proposals, 1978 - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Katsenelinboigen, Aron J.; Soifer, Valerii; Interviews by Popovskii, Jul. 1988 - 1990 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Interviews with Popovskii, 1981 - 1995 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Fadeev, Aleksandr; Stakhiv, Eugen Samoubiistvo, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Nezabyvaemye, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Zachem Prozaiku Stikhi, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Kondratiuk, IUrii Four articles on IUrii Kondratiuk (Samuil Shinger), 1980 - 1989 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Voloshina, Maria Stepanovna Maria Stepanovna, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Piat' Stranits o Razorvannoi Tsepochke, [1992] (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Stranitsy Starogo Dnevnika (on Soiuz Pisatelei SSSR), [1994] (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Otkrovennyi Razgovor (review of letters from readers, summer 1996), Sep. 1996 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Da, Ia Ottuda, No... (on 200th Anniversary of Odessa), Sep. 1994 - Jun. 1997 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Guberman, Igor Drug - Slovo Ser'eznoe, Sep. 1997 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Papa, Mama I Ya, Jun. 1998 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Speeches, 1985 - 2000 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Notes and Drafts, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 37)
- Series V: Research Materials
  - Subseries V.1: Tolstoy and Tolstovtsy
    Mostly undated photostats, part of the materials is in oversized boxes.
    - Belin'kii, Samuil Memoirs (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bulgakov, V. O. U L. N. Tolstogo v poslednii god ego zhizni - memoirs., 1912 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      [With inscription]
    - Levinskii, Edward Memoirs (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Mazurin, Boris Memoirs (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Morgachev, Dimitrii Memoirs (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Poems by Tolstovtsy (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Dragunovskii, Ivan IAkovlevich Materials on Dragunovskii, IAkov (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - IArkov, Ilia Petrovich Memoirs - Part I (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - IArkov, Ilia Petrovich Memoirs - Part III, Chapters 3 - 4 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - IArkov, Ilia Petrovich Memoirs - Part IV (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - IArkov, Ilia Petrovich Memoirs - Part Vii (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Malorod, Anna Memoirs (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Background Material (Box 39, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Subseries V.2: Emigration
    Clippings, notes, printed matter and other materials relating to emigration from the USSR, particularly to the Russian émigré community in the USA
    - Emigration and Re-Emigration Clippings, 1980 - 1993 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Emigration and Re-Emigration Letters, 1978 - 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Emigrants in Soviet Press, 1987- 1991 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Lichnost' v Emigratsii Clippings, 1987 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Segal, Boris Soviet People at home and in America - Article and clippings, 1987 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Russian Writers in Emigration - cllipping, 1985 - 1998 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Adoption of Russian Children in America, [1996] (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Love and Sex in Russian-American Press, 1997 - 1998 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - White Guard - 60 Years Later, 1973 - 1996 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1st and 2nd Wave of Russian Emigration, 1982 - 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 3rd Wave of Russian Emigration - Sociological Research, 1990 - 1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - 3rd Wave of Russian Emigration - Psychological Issues, 1991 - 1993 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 4th Wave of Russian Emigration - Clippings, 1990 - 1992 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 5rd Wave of Russian Emigration - Sociological Research Proposal, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Russian-American Associations, 1979 - 1999 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Lavrov, Lev Novaya Rossiia, 1983 - 1985 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Narodno-Trudovoi Soiuz, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - International Pushkinists Club, [1991] (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Na Drugoi Storone Planety book project, 1991 - 1994 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Proshchanie S Emigratsiei book project, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - My - Zdes' I Tam book project, 1999 - 2000 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Subseries V.3: Writers In Exile
    - Sub-subseries V.3.1: General
      - Pen-Club Center for Writers in Exile, 1986 - 1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Project Background, 1984 - 1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Statistical Analysis (includes SAS printout), 1992 - 1993 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sub-subseries V.3.2: Individuals
      Biographical Information on Individual writers
      - Adamovich, Georgii, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Brodsky, Joseph, 1988 - 1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Broide (Antonov), Edward, 1986 - 1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Chalidse, Valerii, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Dovlatov, Sergei, 1988 - 1990 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Efimov, Igor, 1978 - 1980s (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Elagin, Ivan, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Gorenshtein, Fridrikh, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Gul', Roman, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - IAnovskii, V. S. (Vasilii S.), 1987 - 1989 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Khazanov, Boris (Faibusovich, Gennadii), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Kheifets, Mikhail, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Levitin-Krasnov, A. E. (Anatolii Emmanuilovich), 1984 - 1989 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Maksimov, Vladimir, 1986 - 1991 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Roziner, Feliks, 1985 - 1987 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Rubinshtein, Lev, [1990s] (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Svirskii, Grigorii, 1985 - 1996 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Voinovich, Vladimir, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Vladimov, Georgii, 1986 - 1987 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Volin, Mikhail (Ponomarev, Mikhail), [1989] (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Volkov, Solomon, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Subseries V.4: Notable Individuals
    Research materials on protagonists of Popovskii's books and articles. Alphabetical by name.
    - Cerni, Alexander (Goldstein), 1991 - 1995 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      [Writer. Several of his short stories included]
    - Chalaia, Liudmila, 1990s (Box 18, Folder 2)
      [Painter. Photos removed to Photographs series]
    - Cherniakovskii, Mitchell, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      [Russian emigrant, student of Valley Forge Military Academy]
    - Eniutina, Vera, 1983 - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      [Actress]
    - Guberman, Igor, 1992 - 1997 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      [Poet]
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Background materials on Vladimir Haffkine. Include materials collected by Edythe Lutzker (passed them to Popovskii in 1987), 1915 - 1980s (Box 18, Folder 6)
      [Discoverer of the plague vaccine]
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Transcripts and Translations of writings and letters by Vladimir Haffkine, 1883 - 1927 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Vladimir Haffkine -Trip to the USSR, 1926 - 1928 - Copies and Transcripts (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Vladimir Haffkine - Obituaries and biographical articles, 1930 - 1997 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff; Avidor, Samuel; Behr, Golda; Joffe, Hillel; Liber, M; Tedesco, Beatrice; Zhosselson, Ilia Memoirs about Vladimir Haffkine, 1915 - 1980s (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff; Lutzker, Edythe Book commissioned by Edythe Lutzker, author unknown. Chapters 11 - 12, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Haffkine, Waldemar Mordecai Wolff Photocopies of 1910 - 1911 letters to Haffkine from family (in Russian) (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Kalina, Aleksandr Energy, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      [Inventor of Kalina Cycleimproving the efficiency of electric power generators]
    - Katsenelinboigen, Aron J. University of Pennsylvania, 1988 - 1997 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      [Economist]